<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Project introduction on Beer Data analysis</title><link>https://luca2618.github.io/social_website/</link><description>Recent content in Project introduction on Beer Data analysis</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><atom:link href="https://luca2618.github.io/social_website/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Data</title><link>https://luca2618.github.io/social_website/data-description/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://luca2618.github.io/social_website/data-description/</guid><description>To delve into the intriguing world of beer reviews, we are leveraging the extensive Beer Advocate dataset. This dataset is derived from a popular app and encompasses over 1.5 million beer reviews collected over a decade, concluding in November 2011. Each review provides detailed assessments across five key dimensions: appearance, aroma, palate, taste, and overall impression. Our analysis primarily aims to decode the overall impression of each beer, identifying trends and patterns that capture what beer enthusiasts truly value.</description></item><item><title>Network analysis</title><link>https://luca2618.github.io/social_website/network-analysis/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://luca2618.github.io/social_website/network-analysis/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Text analysis</title><link>https://luca2618.github.io/social_website/text-analysis/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://luca2618.github.io/social_website/text-analysis/</guid><description>Textual Analysis of Beer Reviews Introduction: In our social science project, we embarked on a textual analysis of beer reviews to explore patterns of community formation based on preferences in beer consumption. Through this analysis, we aimed to understand the underlying characteristics and sentiments associated with different beer choices within distinct communities.
Community Identification: Upon analyzing the beer reviews, we identified three distinct communities based on commonalities in beer preferences and review sentiments.</description></item></channel></rss>