<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Project introduction on Beer Data analysis</title><link>https://luca2618.github.io/social_website/</link><description>Recent content in Project introduction on Beer Data analysis</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><atom:link href="https://luca2618.github.io/social_website/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Data</title><link>https://luca2618.github.io/social_website/data-description/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://luca2618.github.io/social_website/data-description/</guid><description>To delve into the intriguing world of beer reviews, we are leveraging the extensive Beer Advocate dataset. This dataset is derived from the beeradvocate forum and contains 1.5 million beer reviews starting from November 2011. Each review provides a score across five key qualities: appearance, aroma, palate, taste, and overall impression, along with a written text where the reviewer can elaborate on their oppinions and the qualities of the beer. Our analysis aims to decode what qualities of a beer people prefer, as well as identifying communities of people with different tastes in beers.</description></item><item><title>Network analysis</title><link>https://luca2618.github.io/social_website/network-analysis/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://luca2618.github.io/social_website/network-analysis/</guid><description>Constructing the Network The network we created from dataset, consisted of 2 types of nodes. Person nodes and beer nodes, each interlinked by a person review of a beer. Ultimately we were interessted in communities of beer drinkers, and therefore projected the network onto the people nodes. Furthermore we weighted each edge between 2 people with the sum of an agreement score for each beer they shared.
Network properties The network end up being completely connected, meaning that there are no distinc sets of people driking only distincs sets of beers.</description></item><item><title>Text analysis</title><link>https://luca2618.github.io/social_website/text-analysis/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://luca2618.github.io/social_website/text-analysis/</guid><description>Textual Analysis of Beer Reviews Introduction: In our social science project, we embarked on a textual analysis of beer reviews to explore patterns of community formation based on preferences in beer consumption. Through this analysis, we aimed to understand the underlying characteristics and sentiments associated with different beer choices within distinct communities.
Community Identification: Upon analyzing the beer reviews, we identified three distinct communities based on commonalities in beer preferences and review sentiments.</description></item></channel></rss>